Preliminary Inventory to the Lawrence Fertig Papers, 1943-1978
Hoover Institution Archives
Lawrence Fertig Papers,
1943-1978
78112
Fertig, Lawrence
6 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 2 motion picture film reels, 9 phonotapes (7.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, correspondence, printed matter, sound recordings, and motion picture film, relating to U.S. and international economic policy, and laissez-faire economics
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1978.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Economic policy.; International economic relations.; Laissez-faire.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-; United States--Economic policy.; Moving-pictures.; Phonotapes.; Journalists.
Container List
- Accuracy in Media (Box 1.)
  - America's Future, Inc.
  - American Civil Liberties Union
  - American-African affairs
  - Anderson, Martin
  - Mises, Ludwig von
    - Portrait
    - Library
    - Obituaries
    - Correspondence
    - Foundations contributing to his projects
    - Festschrift and other honors
  - Committee for Economic Development
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer
  - Baruch, Bernard
  - Burgess, W. R. (U.S. Treasury)
  - Brozen, Yale
  - Burns, Arthur
  - Colleges and universities (Correspondence)
  - General and miscellaneous
  - Conservative Party
  - Cortney, Philip
- Hayek, Friedrich (Box 2.)
  - Dahlberg, Arthur G.
  - Davenport, John
  - Federal Reserve
  - Foundation for Economic Education
  - Friedman, Milton
  - Hahn, Albert
  - Goldwater, Barry
  - Haberler, G.
  - Gainsbrugh, Martin H.
  - Hahn, Nicolaus and Nora
  - Harriman, Averell
  - New York University
    - Resignation from Board
      - General
      - Publicity
      - Miscellaneous
    - General, 1962-1976
- Heller, Walter (Box 3.)
  - India
  - Institute of Economic Affairs (London)
  - Peterson, William H.
  - Hicks, Orton (Dartmouth)
  - Human Events
  - Hutt, W. H.
  - Javits, Ben
  - Keynes, John M.
  - Levine, Isaac Don
  - McLearn, Bill
  - Lyons, Gene (Readers Digest)
  - McArthur, Charles
  - Petro, Sylvester
  - Philadelphia Society (Don Lipsett)
  - Norwegian publications
  - Perlo, Victor
  - Right to work
  - Roepke, Wilhelm
  - Rueff, Jacques
  - Rimanoczy, Richard
  - Rusk, Dean
  - Rogge, Ben
  - Saulnier, Raymond
  - Tullner, Dan (Cornell alumni)
  - Sennholz, Hans
  - West, Rebecca
  - Wedemeyer, General A.C.
  - Wilson, C.E. (General Motors)
  - "Right Premise - Wrong Conclusion," The Freeman, Jan. 1967
  - World-Telegram and other papers (Column)
  - Fortnight Magazine (Reprints)
- World-Telegram (Correspondence) (Box 4.)
  - Columbia Features (Correspondence)
  - Column correspondence
  - Speeches
    - Commonwealth Club, Oct. 21, 1966
    - Rockford College, Dec. 1972
    - CBS
    - Conservative Party, 1966
    - Women's Republican Club, Jan. 27, 1966
    - Economic Club of Detroit, May 1, 1961
    - Society of the Four Arts, March 2, 1971
    - Employers Association, Milwaukee, Apr. 13, 1972
    - Statement on educational policy, 1971-72
    - Meet the Press, 1965-66
    - Women Investors, Nov. 9, 1965
    - U.S. Chamber of Commerce, Apr. 28, 1965
    - New York Federation of Women's Clubs, Feb. 26, 1964
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Dec. 3, 1964
    - Committee for Monetary Research and Education, Nov. 14, 1974
  - New York University Men-in-Finance Club, 1965-68 (Box 5.)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963-67
    - Invitations to speak
  - Mont Pelerin
    - 1973-
      - The Image of the Entrepreneur in the U.S., 1970
      - General
  - Miscellaneous printed matter
- Stepelevich, Lawrence S., ed., The Capitalist Reader (Box 6.)
  - New York State Temporary Commission on Educational Finances, Final Report, 1956
  - The Incredible Bread Machine
  - Fertig, Lawrence, Prosperity through Freedom
  - Wiegand, G. Carl, ed., The Menace of Inflation
  - What's Past Is Prologue
- Scrapbook I, 1944-1949 (Box 7.)
- Scrapbook II, 1949-1952
- Scrapbook IV, 1963-1966
- Scrapbook III, 1953-1962 (Box 8.)
- Scrapbook V, 1966-1967 (Box 9.)
- Scrapbook on Prosperity through Freedom